

You get what you give

MARCO CALOBA

Data Analyst

Personal website

in LinkdIn

GitHub

Linktree

■ marco caloba@hotmail.com

M Medium

SKILLS

Python Django Git

HTML CSS Notion

Excel Power BI SQL

SELF-STUDY

Online Courses

- Full-Stack Engineer Codecademy (undergoing)
- Python Web Apps with Django - Codecademy
- Google Data Analytics Coursera
- Data Analysis with Python freeCodeCamp
- SQL for Data Analysis Udacity
- Become a Power BI Data Analyst - Microsoft
- Introduction to Python Programming – Udacity

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Native English: Fluent

TRAITS

Organisation | Planning

Curiosity | Proactiveness

Communication | Focus

Consistency | Discipline

HOBBIES

Read Gym



ABOUT ME

I am a hard working guy that is immensely curious about the world of technology. I have developed important skills studying engineering and working, but I believe that what makes me stand out from the most are both my work ethic and interpersonal skills. I am highly organised, I have great planning skills, and I am able to work consistently with high standards. What I don't have in experience, I will definitely make up for in hustle. I also believe that it is people who make or brake a business, so I do my best to always be a source of positive energy. With my drive to learn and improve, I am confident that I can become a valuable contributor to any team's success.

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst | Miranda & Irmão

Feb 2023 - Present

MS Excel, Python & Power BI

I help the company transform product and client data into profitable pricing strategies. I use Excel and Python to clean and analyse data, and Power BI to create reports and presentations for the decision-makers. Regular communication with stakeholders to present data analyses and defend pricing recommendations is a key part of my role.

R&D Engineer | Miranda & Irmão

Sep 2022 - Feb 2023

MS Excel

In this role, I designed new products based on customer requests. I worked on multiple projects at once and collaborated with cross-functional teams, communicating technical information to colleagues and management. My tasks included designing concepts, testing prototypes, analysing data, and ensuring successful product implementation.

PROJECTS

You can find in depth information on all of my projects by clicking the title above.

Traffic Monitoring REST API | Streamlining data for traffic dashboard

Nov 2023

Python, Django & PostgreSQL

This project centred on building a REST API with Django Rest Framework for a road traffic monitoring dashboard. The API manages road segments, capturing data such as average vehicle speed, traffic intensity characterisation, and timestamps of recordings.

Kobo to Notion | Automating my reading highlights

May 2023

Python & Notion

I developed a Python script to automate extracting and organising book highlights. The program reads a file from my Kobo e-reader and connects with Notion's API to send the information directly to my books database. This saves me plenty of time and streamlines my note-taking process with my Notion's second brain.

EDUCATION

Masters Degree in Mechanical Engineering | University of Aveiro

Sep 2017 - Jul 2022